<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Analysis of Pesticides in Food and Environmental Samples edited by Jose L. Tadeo on FenXiHuaXue Handbook</title>
    <link>https://example.com/categories/Analysis-of-Pesticides-in-Food-and-Environmental-Samples-edited-by-Jose-L.-Tadeo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Analysis of Pesticides in Food and Environmental Samples edited by Jose L. Tadeo on FenXiHuaXue Handbook</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/categories/Analysis-of-Pesticides-in-Food-and-Environmental-Samples-edited-by-Jose-L.-Tadeo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>APCI General Review</title>
      <link>https://example.com/docs/01-Mass-Spec-LC-MS/Part-01-Theory/APCI_general_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/docs/01-Mass-Spec-LC-MS/Part-01-Theory/APCI_general_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The LC elute passing through a nebulizing needle, creates a fine spray.  The spray passes through a heated ceramic tube, where the droplets are fully vaporized.  The resulting gas/vapor mixture is then passed over a corona discharge needle, where the solvent vapor is ionized to create reagent gas ions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For successful APCI, the analyte must be volatile and thermally stable and the mobile phase must be suitable for gas-phase acid–base reactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To vaporize the solvent and analyte, the APCI source is typically operated at vaporizer temperatures of 400 to 500 &lt;sup&gt;0&lt;/sup&gt;C.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ESI General Review</title>
      <link>https://example.com/docs/01-Mass-Spec-LC-MS/Part-01-Theory/ESI_general_review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://example.com/docs/01-Mass-Spec-LC-MS/Part-01-Theory/ESI_general_review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The LC eluate is sprayed into a spray chamber at atmospheric pressure in the presence of a strong electrostatic field and heated drying gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electrostatic field occurs between the nebulizer, which is the ES probe, and the capillary. Aerosol of charged droplet formation at right angles to the capillary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ionization takes place as a result of imparting the strong electrical field and the superheated nitrogrn sheath gas, with Agilent AJS (Jet Stream) technology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
